前情提要
我准备和比利·肯波合作
I intend to do business with Billy Kimber.
这里有个叫谢尔比的人吗
Is there any man here named Shelby?
我准备扩张  进军赌马生意
I am planning an expansion. Onto the racetracks.
如果能跟你合作真的很荣幸  肯波先生
It would be an honour to work with you, Mr Kimber.
没人可以跟我合作
Nobody works with me.
都只能在我手下工作
People work FOR me.
丹尼  你是个好人  也是个优秀的士兵
'Danny, you are a good man and a good soldier.'
是  军士长
Yes, Sergeant Major.
我名单上的第一个人就是弗莱迪·索恩
Freddie Thorne is at the very top of my list.
划掉他吧  他不会再回这个城市了
Well, cross him off. He won't be returning to this city.
我们哪儿都不去  艾达
We're not going anywhere, Ada.
我们要留在这里
We are going to stay here
我们就在这儿结婚  带着我们的孩子
and we'll marry here, with our baby.
我不怕汤米·谢尔比
I'm not afraid of Tommy Shelby.
汤玛斯
Thomas,
你敢把枪卖给任何一个能发挥其用武之地的人
you sell those guns to anyone who has use for them,
你就死定了
you will hang.
把它们扔到警察能找到的地方
Dump them somewhere the police can find them.
不
No.
汤玛斯·谢尔比现在是
Thomas Shelby is now the beginning,
你任务的全部内容
middle and end of your mission.
我该做什么
So what shall I do?
你必须不择手段地接近他
You must do everything you can to get close to him.
找件漂亮的礼服
Dig out a nice dress.
我带你去赛马会
I want to take you to the races.
但我想提醒你  我会让你心碎的
I warn you, I'll break your heart.
我心已碎
Already broken.
给我一瓶威士忌和三个杯子
Give me a bottle of whiskey and three glasses please.
-苏格兰还是爱尔兰产的  -爱尔兰的
- Scotch or Irish? - Irish.
我决定不去了
I've decided not to go.
那个赛马会
To the races.
除非你再加两英镑
Not unless you give me another two pounds,
十先令来付礼服钱
ten shillings towards the dress.
我已经给过你三英镑了
I've already given you three.
你到时候穿的西装会值多少钱
How much did you pay for the suit you'll be wearing?
我不会花钱买西装
Oh, I don't pay for suits.
我的西装都是店家赠送的
My suits are on the house
不然我就烧了他的铺子
or the house burns down.
你想让我穿得跟卖花女一样吗
So you want me to go looking like a flower girl?
我怎么想都无所谓
What I want makes no difference.
你穿着打扮可不是为了我
It's not me you're dressing up for.
浴   血
黑   帮
第一季   『人人影视英剧社倾情奉献』   第三集
谢尔比先生  如果我太迷恋这酒  你可得见谅
You'll forgive me, Mr Shelby, if I indulge a little.
请自便
Please.
一个来自史巴伯洛克区的人
It takes a lot for a man from Sparkbrook
想走进这酒吧可需要不少勇气
to step inside this pub.
任何有钱  无意捣乱的人
Anyone with money and good intentions
在加里森酒吧都会受到欢迎的
is welcome in the Garrison.
你之前说有正事要谈
Now...you said you had business.
那事不能明说  谢尔比先生
It's delicate, Mr Shelby.
是关于某人知道某事的相关情况的问题
It's a question of who knows what about what.
跟不远处的伯明翰轻兵器工厂有关
It concerns the factory down the road, at the BSA.
你或许也知道
As you might know,
那边大多数油漆车间里面都是爱尔兰人
most of the paint shop there is Irish.
像那种大地方  谣言很容易传播的
Big old place like that, rumours get started.
据谣传  发生了一起盗窃案
Rumours that there was a robbery.
什么东西被盗了
Robbery of what?
枪支  谢尔比先生  大量的枪支
Guns, Mr Shelby. A serious amount of guns.
那跟我有什么关系
What business is that of mine?
在推测方面
When it comes to speculation,
谁也比不上工厂的夜班工人
you can't beat a factory night shift.
有些人说  打样车间有小道消息流传
Some say there was word from the proofing bay
说那些枪是被剃刀党的人劫走了
it was the Peaky Blinders who took them.
你那些夜班工人一定是在做梦
Your night shift must be dreaming.
-或许是的  -或许也不是
- Maybe they are. - Maybe they're not.
我们想说的是  谢尔比先生
What we are trying to say is, Mr Shelby,
如果你耳闻了我们刚说的那东西的下落
that if you were to hear about the whereabouts of said items...
我们愿意出大价钱
We'd pay good money.
你们有很多钱吗
You have good money?
我们有从酒吧征集的捐款
We have collections from the pubs.
你们是代表谁在谈
For who do you speak?
-爱尔兰人民  -爱尔兰共和军
- The people of Ireland. - The Irish Republican Army.
-当真吗  -绝逼当真
- For a fact? - For a fucking fact.
你以为我们是在开玩笑吗
You think we're jokers?
我难道笑了吗
Am I laughing?
*父亲啊父亲  你为何如此悲伤*
*Oh, father, why are you so sad*
*在这晴朗的复活节清晨*
*On this bright Easter morn'... *
麦格瑞  你能闭嘴吗
Maguire, will you shut up?
*爱尔兰人何时才能*
*When Irishmen are proud and glad*
*为生他养他的祖国感到骄傲*
*Of the land where they were born? *
麦格瑞  你个该死的  我们要谈正经事呢
Maguire, away and shite man, we're trying to talk business...
*儿子啊儿子  我突然想起*
*Oh, son, I see sad mem'ries view*
*过去的痛苦回忆*
*Of far-off distant days
*当我和你一样还是个孩子时*
*When being just a boy like you*
*我加入了爱尔兰共和军*
*I joined the IRA.*
太精彩了
Bravo!
好了  够了
All right, boys.
如果我听到关于那事的什么消息
If I hear anything about who knows what about what,
我会通知你的
I'll let you know.
*我的宝贝啊  我好想再见到*
*Gra mo chree, I long to see*
*共和军的那些战士*
*The boys of the old IRA... *
我以为你只允许周六那天唱歌呢
I thought you only allowed singing on a Saturday.
威士忌有很好的验证作用
Whiskey is good proofing water.
能够告诉你谁是真的  谁是假的
It tells you who's real and who isn't.
我的那些同胞们想要什么
And what did my countrymen want?
他们只是无名小卒罢了
They're nobodies.
他们通常在史巴伯洛克区的黑天鹅酒吧混
They drink in The Black Swan in Sparkbrook.
他们成为叛军  只是因为喜欢那些歌罢了
They're only rebels because they like the songs.
你同情他们吗
You have sympathies with them?
我对任何人东西都没有同情
I have no sympathies of any description.
他们的口音好重
Their accents were so thick,
不知道你能不能听得懂
it's a wonder you could understand them.
下次的话  我可以帮忙翻译
Next time, I could translate.
你愿意替我做事吗
You'd work for me?
我以为我已经在替你做事了呢
I thought I already was.
所以你愿意去参加赛马会
So you are coming to the races?
两英镑  十先令
Two pounds, ten shillings.
十先令
Ten shillings.
买件红色的衣服
Buy something red.
和他的手帕搭配
To match his handkerchief.
谁的手帕
Whose handkerchief?
艾达  你搞什么啊
Ada, what the hell?
我鼓足勇气穿着婚纱跑过他们的势力范围
I dared myself to run through their territory in my dress.
你疯了吗
Are you mad?
是啊  气得要疯了
Yeah. Mad as hell with all of them.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you too.
他们越是想阻碍我们  我就会越疯狂
The more they try to stop us, the madder I'll be.
-来吧小公主  牧师在等着了  -等等
- Come on, princess, the vicar's waiting. - Wait...
我看起来怎么样
How do I look?
宛若天使
Like an angel.
莫斯
Moss?
我们掌握了关于黑天鹅酒吧的什么信息吗
What do we know about The Black Swan?
有个卧底提供情报说
An operative has provided intelligence
那里是爱尔兰共和军的聚集地
that it is a place where IRA men gather.
就是些醉醺醺的船员在那儿唱歌而已  长官
It's just a lot of drunken navigators singing songs, sir.
爱尔兰共和军才不会去那种地方
The IRA wouldn't go near them.
那那里怎么会有两个人要买枪呢
Then why are two of them looking to buy guns?
那两人叫什么
Do you have names?
什么事都要她帮你打点好吗
Must she do everything for you?
"她"  长官
"She", sir?
事实证明  一个女卧底
One female operative has proved more useful
比你们这些壮汉都有用
than any of you great lumps of men.
我们是正规警察  长官  不是间谍
We are regular police officers, sir. Not spies.
只有发生了罪案  我们才能行动
We can only act when a crime has been committed.
也许我该派些人
Perhaps I should send some men
去黑天鹅酒吧查问一下
down to The Black Swan to ask questions.
然后打草惊蛇吗
And scare them all into hiding?
并非上策  警长
Not the best of tactics, Sergeant.
我的策略源自我在法国的经历
My tactics come from my experiences in France.
我那些大块头手下大多也在法国服过役  长官
Most of my great lumps of men served in France too, sir.
我每天都为国鞠躬尽瘁
I serve my country every day.
没其它事了  警长
That will be all, Sergeant.
滚远点
Away and shite!
爱上我了是吗
Fancy me, do ya?
你是什么人  警察吗
What are you? A copper?
臭婊子
Proddy bitch!
我见过你  你是加里森酒吧的侍应生
I've seen you. I've seen your face, serving in the Garrison.
过来
Come here...
我要代表爱尔兰自由邦
I am taking you in for interrogation
把你带回去审问
on behalf of the Irish Free State.
行了吧
All right?
你带武器了吗
Are you armed?
没有
No.
那我就告诉你
Then I'll tell you.
艾达和弗莱迪·索恩今天结婚了
Ada and Freddie Thorne were married today.
他们没听你的  留在了这里
They defied your orders, they haven't left the city.
我会处理的
I'll deal with it.
汤玛斯  让我来处理
Thomas...I'll deal with it.
他们在哪
Where are they?
弗莱迪的同志提供的安全屋
Freddie's comrades have safe houses.
你为何打听这个
Why do you want to know?
我想送些花过去  不然呢
I want to send them flowers. Why do you think?
他们留下来有那么糟吗
Would it be so bad if they stayed?
我保证会让弗莱迪离开的
I promised I'd run Freddie out of town.
向谁保证
Promised who?
我跟警察说弗莱迪不会再回来
I told the coppers Freddie wouldn't come back.
那是协议的一部分
It's part of the deal.
什么狗日的协议
What bloody deal?
怎么没有家族表决  召开会议
What happened to family votes? What happened to meetings?
要是你把艾达和弗莱迪的事交给我处理
If you let me deal with Ada and Freddie,
大家都能相安无事
it'll end in peace.
你已经饱受战争之苦
Christ knows you've had your fill of war.
一定要让弗莱迪离开这里  波莉
You get Freddie out of town, Poll.
不然我就亲自处理
Or else I'll deal with it myself.
死者在黑天鹅酒吧喝过酒  长官
The victim had been drinking in The Black Swan pub, sir -
就是您提过的那个酒吧
the pub you told me about.
邻里说见到一名年轻女子
And a neighbour said she saw a young woman
离开陈尸现场所在的那条街
leaving the street where the body was found.
一个女人  长官  我在想其中是否有联系
A woman, sir. I was wondering if there was a connection.
什么联系  警长
A connection with what, Sergeant?
您说那位间谍是女人  长官
You said your spy was a woman, sir.
我在想现在针对那些人是不是定了决策
I wondered if now there was now a policy.
格杀勿论  和贝尔法斯特一样
Shoot to kill. Like there was in Belfast.
爱尔兰共和军内部派系众多
The Republicans are famously factional.
他是死于自己人之手
He was killed by one of his own.
就是这样  警长
That will be all, Sergeant.
他们不叫间谍
And they're not called spies.
叫卧底探员
They're called operatives.
是  长官  卧底探员
Operatives, sir. Right, sir.
-你就这样说话  -是啊
- It's how you say things.  - Yeah.
她来这里干什么
What the bloody hell is she doing here?
200英镑  弗莱迪
200 pounds, Freddie.
干什么
For what?
让我们去度一个永不结束的蜜月
For us. For a honeymoon that goes on for ever.
-哪来的钱  -家庭基金
- Where did it come from? - Family fund.
寡妇和绝望的男人兜里的钱
The pockets of widows and desperate men.
理智一点  弗莱迪
See sense, Freddie.
汤米不会放过你们的
Tommy is not going to let this rest.
这年头  家里有个共产主义分子会影响生意
Times like these, a communist in the family is bad for business.
你必须离开这里
You have to leave the city.
-你认为我对付不了汤米·谢尔比  -没错
- You think I can't handle Tommy Shelby? - You can't.
我现在都觉得掌控不了他
I'm having trouble these days
而你还不如我够爷们儿
and I'm twice the man you are.
我去了一趟镇上
I went into town.
库纳德邮轮公司
The Cunard office.
我给你们定了下一班
I booked you both tickets on the next boat
从利物浦去纽约的船票
from Liverpool to New York.
美国啊  弗莱迪
America, Freddie.
他们已经革命过了
They've already had their revolution.
你就不用操心了
You won't have to bother.
两位女士至少得让我考虑一下吧
Will you ladies at least let a man sleep on it?
你无权那么做的
You had no business...
观察和上报  那是你的任务
Observe and report. That is your remit.
我认为有必要知道他的住处
I decided we needed to know where he lived.
我警告过你别让私人情绪
I warned you not to let your personal history
影响判断
cloud your judgment.
你因为他是爱尔兰共和军才跟踪他
You went after him because he was IRA.
我跟着他是因为我以为他身上有情报
I followed him because I thought he might have information.
根据规定
According to the rules,
我应该立即将你撤出加里森街
I should pull you out of Garrison Lane immediately.
不要  切尔滕纳姆赛马就是明天了
No. Cheltenham is tomorrow.
你负担太重了
You take too much upon yourself.
是你说这是现行军事行动
This is an active military mission - your words.
我只是履行职责
I'm doing my job.
格蕾丝  我才不在乎一个芬尼亚会小喽啰的死
Grace, the death of a base Fenian doesn't concern me.
我在乎的是你
Your welfare does.
杀人会让心里蒙上阴影
Killing a man affects the heart.
至于我的心...
And as for my heart...
我知道因为我们两家的关系
I know that because of our family connections,
你私心上会特别关照我
you take my progress personally.
可我不需要你来扮演我父亲的角色
But I don't need you to be my father.
我会想着你的
I will be thinking of you.
-谢尔比先生  -张先生
- Mr Shelby, sir. - Mr Zhang.
那套西装已经卖出去了  先生  今早定下的
That suit is sold, sir. It's being collected this morning.
肯波
我知道
I know.
求你们了  先生们  别在这里打架闹事
Please, gentlemen. No fighting in here.
没事  我们是朋友
It's all right. I come as a friend.
你在为切尔滕纳姆的行程挑选衣服啊
You're collecting your suit for Cheltenham -
很好看
it's very nice.
你他妈是怎么知道的
How the bloody hell do you know?
我知道很多事  肯波先生
I know a lot of things, Mr Kimber.
就像我之前和你说的
And as I told you before,
我很清楚李氏兄弟的勾当
I know the Lee brothers.
我还知道他们也要去切尔滕纳姆赛马会
And I know they're going to be at the Cheltenham races as well.
他们会把钱输在妓女和劣等赛马上
They're going to lose a lot of money on fast women and slow nags.
不  他们打算
No. They're planning on
仗着人多势众  敲诈勒索你的赌注登记人
showing up in numbers and robbing your bookies.
强收粉笔费  欺凌赌注负责人
Running chalk and rafflers.
你觉得我搞不定李氏家族吗
You think I can't handle the Lees?
只是一句朋友的忠告  仅此而已
Just a word of warning from a friend. That's all.
我们切尔滕纳姆见
I'll see you at Cheltenham.
我会从包厢里对你挥手致意的
I'll wave at you from my box.
你要是去赛马会的话
If you're coming to the races,
带上你那位漂亮的酒吧女招待
bring that pretty barmaid of yours.
已经叫了
Already invited.
同志们
Comrades -
大家都知道  像今天这样聚在一起是违法的
as you know, to even gather like this today is illegal.
总督察坎贝尔先生有令
Chief Inspector Campbell has ordered
群体集会人数
that we are not allowed to assemble in groups
不得超过三人
of more than three people.
所以  为了遵守法律
So, to comply with the law,
请大家三人一组站成一堆
please now clump together in groups of three.
你们听到了吗  兄弟们
You hear that, boys?
他们曾吹响同样的哨声让我们超额完成任务
The same whistles they used to blow to send us over the top,
现在他们想驱散我们
they now blow to try and break us up.
所以在特派员到来之前
So before the Specials get here,
所有想罢工的人们  举起手来
raise a hand, all those who want to strike...
现在解散吧  解散然后带着口信回家
Now disperse! Disperse and take the message home!
只要我们团结一致  就永不会被打败
United, we will never be defeated!
汤米  汤米
Tommy! Oi, Tommy.
到底发生了什么事
What the hell's been happening?
警察刚才突袭了一个工厂非法集会
The police had just raided a rally at the factory.
你说是不是弗莱迪·索恩回来了
You thinking Freddie Thorne's back?
他是回来了  和艾达一起
I know he is. And he's with Ada.
要想找到伯明翰唯一的
How hard can it be to find
一位穿着4英寸高跟鞋的姑娘能有多难呢
the only girl in Birmingham with four-inch heels, eh?
她和共产主义分子在一起
She's with the commies.
城里到处都有他们的窝点
They have little rat holes all over the city.
我只想知道她在哪儿
I just want to know where she is.
汤米  你最好和亚瑟谈谈
Tommy, you'd best have a word with Arthur as well.
亚瑟又怎么了
What's wrong with bloody Arthur?
他又抑郁了
He's got the Flanders blues again.
人们一直问东问西的  我根本不知道答案
People keep asking me questions that I don't know the answer to.
你们家艾达结婚了  是真的吗
"Is it true your Ada got married?"
我说  我不知道
I say, "I don't know."
她现在住在哪里
"Where is she living now?"
我不知道
"I don't know."
亚瑟
"Arthur...
黑天鹅酒吧的爱尔兰人是谁杀的
"Who killed the Paddy from The Black Swan?"
我说  什么爱尔兰人
I go, "What Paddy?"
他们说
They say...
是你们剃刀党
"Is it you, Peaky Blinders,
把枪从伯明翰轻武器工厂偷走的吗
who stole the guns from the BSA?"
什么枪  汤米
What guns, Tommy?
亚瑟  你被毒打之后  我觉得你需要休息
Arthur, after your beating, I thought you needed a break...
他妈的枪是怎么回事  汤米
What bloody guns, Tommy?!
亚瑟  我本来打算告诉你的
Arthur, I was going to tell you.
你本来打算告诉我的
You were going to tell me.
亚瑟  听我说
Arthur, listen to me.
你过去几年一直过得很艰难
You've had a hard time these past few years.
上帝知道
God knows you have.
你需要好好休息
You deserve some rest.
我们运气不错  交好运了
We had some luck. Some bloody luck.
上天把大批武器交到我们手上
It fell off a wagon into our laps.
你只需要知道
And all you need to know is,
现在手握机枪的是我们
it's us that has the machine guns now.
焦头烂额的是他们
And it's them that's in the mud.
明白吗
All right?
来吧  我有个惊喜给你
Come on. I have a surprise for you.
来吧
Come on.
惊喜  在哪儿呢
A surprise? Where is she?
你一直想要什么来着  亚瑟
What is it you've always wanted, Arthur? Eh?
我们在法国时  你经常说
When we were in France, you used to say,
等我回到英国  我要自己开一家酒吧
"When I get back to England, I want to own my own pub."
你变了  你现在通人情了  汤米
You've gone soft. You've gone soft, Tommy.
我们怎么知道这里是否出售
How do we know it's for sale?
对我们来说  任何东西都是待售的  亚瑟
Everything's for sale to us, Arthur.
我们现在赚了很多钱
We're making a lot of money these days.
我们需要一个合法生意来洗钱
We need a legitimate business to pass the money from the shop.
我不知道该怎么开酒吧
I wouldn't know what to do.
你三分之二的人生都泡在酒吧里
You've spent two-thirds of your life in pubs.
以前是喝酒  现在是倒酒
Just pour it instead of drinking it.
可我还是能喝酒的  对吧
But I can still drink it, right?
你的酒吧  你说了算
Your pub - you do what you want.
抱歉先生们  我不知道你们来了
Ah - sorry, gentlemen, I didn't hear you come in.
要点什么
What can I get you?
该死的熊孩子
Bloody kids.
另一个车轮也被扎破了
The other one's punctured as well.
坎贝尔先生想要个解释
Mr Campbell wants an explanation.
今天  一些工会煽动分子
Today, some rabble-rouser Union man
在伯明翰轻兵器工发动了一场罢工
brought the BSA out on strike.
是弗莱迪·索恩干的
It was Freddie Thorne.
我以为你答应过他不会回来了
I thought you promised he wouldn't come back.
我知道他在城里  我正在处理此事
I know he's in town. I'm dealing with it.
坎贝尔督察以为你能管好自己的地盘
Inspector Campbell thought you controlled your territories.
没错
Yeah.
我说了  我正在处理
I said I'm dealing with it.
我听说
I heard that, er...
弗莱迪和你妹妹结婚了
Freddie married your sister.
你的家庭成员可真牛啊
Some family you've got, eh?
我猜你等不及过圣诞节了
Bet you can't wait for Christmas.
把弗莱迪·索恩交给我们
Deliver Freddie Thorne to us
否则我们就把你妹妹算作共犯
or we'll take your sister in as an accomplice.
她将因煽动骚乱去蹲个4年
She'll get four years for sedition.
或者你把他交出来  你妹妹就没事了
Or you can turn him in and your sister goes free.
我先告辞了  汤姆
I'll say good night then, Tom.
你看到弗莱迪·索恩了吗
Have you seen Freddie Thorne?
-没有  -那汤米呢
- No. - Or Tommy?
-我得找到弗莱迪  -先把这杯喝了吧
- I have to find Freddie. - Drink this first.
不  我必须找到他们
No, I have to find them,
我觉得他们要互相残杀了
I think they are going to kill each other.
等等
Wait.
谁要杀谁
Who is going to kill who?
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
你到底想怎么样  弗莱迪
What exactly is it that you want, Freddie?
我是来告诉你
I came to tell you...
你这样做是没用的  汤米
That's not going to work, Tommy.
波莉来过了  她给了我这些
Polly came round. She gave me that.
波莉一定是脑充血了
Well, Polly must have had a rush of blood.
也可能是酒喝多了
Or port wine.
我很欣赏你的坦诚
Your honesty is appreciated.
如果你不想利用这些
Now, if you're not going to use that thing...
我还没说完  坐下
I'm not finished. Sit down.
坐下  快坐
Sit down. Sit.
跟我说说枪的事
Talk to me about the guns.
你还记得我们以前常常跳进去
Do you remember we used to jump in here,
比赛谁游得最快吗
see who could swim the fastest...?
我是来谈正事的  汤米
I'm here to talk business, Tommy.
你觉得我们还能那样吗
Do you reckon we could still do it?
你害艾达怀上了你的孽种
You loaded Ada with your bastard
就因为她是谢尔比家族的人
because she's a Shelby.
你以为这意味着你也能成个人物
You thought it'd mean you'd be somebody.
我不会让你为了革命事业毁了我妹妹的一生
I won't let you fuck up my sister's life for your cause.
天呐
My God.
你居然这么认为
You actually believe that.
我爱她  汤米
I love her, Tommy.
我爱上她的时候  她才9岁  我也只有12岁
I've loved her since she was nine and I was 12.
她也一样爱我
And she loves me the same.
你知道连什么是爱都不知道吧
You even know the word?
你们的婚姻不会持久的
This marriage will not stand.
弗莱迪不要你的钱
Freddie didn't want your money.
现在警察说  如果我们不交出弗莱迪
And now the coppers are saying if we don't turn Freddie in,
他们会把艾达的名字也印在逮捕令上
they'll put Ada on the arrest warrant as well.
你的同情心就是这样的结果  波莉
That's where your compassion gets you, Poll.
从现在起  我们得按我的方法行事
From now on, we do it my way.
否则呢
Or what?
准备好了吗
Ready?
他们靠近过来了
They're getting closer.
我来领头
I'll lead.
-小心点  丹尼  -汤米
- Watch yourself, Danny. - Tommy.
小心点  丹尼
Be careful, Danny.
汤米
Tommy!
Tommy?
汤米
Tommy!
Tommy?
门是开着的
It's open.
二等兵向您报告  长官
Private Whizz Bang reporting, sir.
稍息
At ease.
伦敦方面有什么消息
So, what news from London?
我去了一家酒吧  名叫红帽妈妈
I was in a pub - it was called Mother Redcap.
一家爱尔兰酒吧
An Irish pub.
我跟一些老家伙聊起了伯明翰的事
I got talking to some old bloke about Birmingham.
他说现在出麻烦了  一个爱尔兰共和军成员被枪杀
He said there's been trouble. An IRA man shot.
他说了很多  但我只听到一点
He said a lot, but the only bit I heard...
就是他们的最高指挥部认为
was that their high command
是剃刀党开枪杀的人
think it's the Peaky Blinders who shot him.
我立马登上最近的一班船来提醒你
Came up on the next boat to warn you.
是真的吗
Is it true?
不是
No.
但流言比真相传得快
But lies travel faster than the truth.
给他们传个口信
Get a message to them.
让他们派个人来谈判
Tell them to send someone to parley.
告诉他们这其中有误会
Tell them there's been a misunderstanding
我们不想惹麻烦
and we don't want any trouble.
你的麻烦已经够多了  对吧  汤米
You've got enough trouble - right, Tommy?
又是威士忌又是大麻
A whisky and a smoke.
我闻得出那种味道
I can smell it in the air.
我自己有时也会抽点
I use it sometimes myself.
我称之为"私人甜心"
I call it "My sweetheart".
他们派给我们最糟糕的任务  汤米
They gave us the worst job, Tommy.
是啊
Yeah...
而且我们他妈还是自愿的
..And we fucking volunteered.
有时  梦境会持续一整晚
Sometimes, it lasts all night.
我躺在这里
I lie here
听着他们用铲子和镐
and I listen to the shovels and the picks
挖那面墙的声音
against that wall there.
我祈祷着他们挖进来之前
And I pray the sun will come up at the curtains
太阳已经升起来了
before they break through.
不  我从不祈祷  而是希望
'No, I don't pray - I hope.
有时候能实现
'And sometimes, it happens.
太阳先升起来了
'The sun beats them.
但是大多时候
'But mostly...
是铲子挖通了墙
'The shovels beat the sun.'
我会尽我的职责  长官
你妹妹之前来过这里
Your sister was here.
她非常担心你和弗莱迪
She was worried. You and Freddie.
害她吐了
It had made her sick...
她现在没事了  但她现在这种情况
She's all right, but in her condition,
非常需要安宁
she needs peace.
女人间的谈话
Women talk.
女人就那样
That is something they do.
她说了一些关于你的事
She talked about you.
她说你有什么事都紧锁在心里
She said you keep everything locked up.
男人就这样
Well, that's what men do.
你妹妹人很好  我喜欢她
Your sister's nice. I like her.
她也挺不容易的
It can't be easy for her.
她的哥哥和丈夫  为同样一件事争斗
Her brother and her husband, fighting over the same thing.
男人有话也该说出来
Men should talk, too.
对你说吗
To you?
有何不可
Why not?
我是酒吧女招待  这是我的工作
I'm a barmaid. It's my job.
男人总喜欢把烦恼告诉酒吧女招待
Men always tell their troubles to a barmaid.
你和弗莱迪到底在为什么争斗
What is it you and Freddie are fighting over?
我明早9点来这里接你
I'll meet you here at nine o'clock tomorrow morning.
你买礼服了吗
Did you buy a dress?
是的  我买了礼服
Yes. I bought a dress.
是什么样的
How does it look?
他加满了油  也增加了润滑
He's changed the oil and greased her up.
可以一直开到切尔滕纳姆  是吗科利
So will it get me all the way to Cheltenham, Curly?
他很擅长修汽车  但那让他觉得难受
He's good with motors, but it pains him.
汽车没有感情  我没办法跟它沟通
No heart in motorcars. I can't talk with them.
是啊  汤米或许会需要快速大逃亡呢
Yeah - Tommy might need to make a fast getaway.
李氏家族的人会挤满赛马场的
The Lees will be all over the track.
以及肯波的手下  以及那些警察
And Kimber's men. And his coppers.
他们是那里的掌权者  汤米
They control the law down there, Tommy.
摇启发动机试试  查理
Give her a turn for me, Charlie.
这辆车只能坐4个人
This car only seats four.
你要想活着回来  可不能只带4个人去
You'll need more men than that if you're to come back alive.
只有我和一个女孩单独去
It'll be just me and a girl.
就我们两个去参加赛马会吗
Is it just the two of us going to the races?
差不多吧
Something like that.
立正
Attention!
好了
Right.
这是在大行动之前做最后的简报
This is what was known as the final briefing before going over the top.
沿着那条路走60英里就是切尔滕纳姆的赛马场
60 miles down that road is Cheltenham racetrack.
约翰尼  我们的任务是什么
Johnny, what's our mission, boy?
干倒李氏家族  亚瑟
To stick it to the Lee family, Arthur.
说的好
That's right.
李氏家族的人想从合法赛马业中骗钱
The Lees are skimming money off legal bookies.
强收粉笔费  盗卖博彩  毒打那些不肯买的人
Running chalk, selling rafflers, beating up them as won't buy.
但今天  我们要阻止他们
But today, we're going to stop them.
肯波的手下怎么了
What about Kimber's men?
我觉得他好像有安保团队
I thought he had his own protection.
肯波的手下都堕落腐败了
Kimber's let his troops go rotten.
他们收受李氏家族的贿赂  睁只眼闭只眼
They're on the take from the Lees to look the other way.
我们要向肯波展示该怎么对付那些人
We are going to show Kimber how it should be done.
现在拿上你们擅长的武器
Now take what you're good at.
你们当中带枪的  最好不要用
Those of you with guns, keep them out of it,
除非有人拿枪指着你
unless a gun is pulled on you.
我们要安静地完成这事
We want this done quietly.
我们什么时候分钱
So when do we share out the cash?
我们不分  不能拿那些钱
We don't. We're not keeping the cash.
你们现在加入汤米的队伍了  伙计们
You're in Tommy's army now, boys.
只能相信家族内部成员
Trust only kin.
出发吧
Let's go.
你确定我们可以进来吗
Are you sure we're allowed in here?
我更喜欢走后门进入赛马场
Well, I prefer to come to the races the back way.
那可以免去不少麻烦
It keeps me out of trouble.
赛马场是个无法无天的地方
Tracks are lawless places.
我受不了小打小闹的犯罪分子  这边走
I can't stand petty criminals. This way.
我们可以押注吗
Will we get to lay a bet?
不能  赌博是流氓恶棍才玩的
No - gambling is for mugs.
这边走
This way...
你该庆幸是跟我在一起
You're lucky you're with me
否则你把钱押在被操纵的比赛上就浪费了
or you'd be wasting your money on fixed races.
我一直很好奇  你会如何操纵比赛
I always wondered, how do you fix a race?
我怎么知道
How should I know?
-好了  你来说  -什么
- OK, you do the talking. - What?
告诉安保人员  你是莎拉·杜根小姐
Tell security you are Lady Sarah Duggan...
借过  借过
Excuse us, excuse us...
康尼马拉的莎拉·杜根小姐
Lady Sarah Duggan of Connemara.
你跑出来找你那匹马的骑手  结果迷路了
You got lost when you went to look for the boy
你的马叫做  娇花
riding your horse - Dandy Flower.
如果他们问起我  就说我是个普鲁士人
If they ask about me, say I'm Prussian
并且不会说英语
and don't speak a word of English.
快点  美丽的小姐  让我的三英镑花的值一点
Come on, posh girl. Earn your three quid.
我还是更喜欢加里森酒吧一点
I still prefer the Garrison.
你会跳舞吗
Do you dance?
除非有人正式邀请我
If I'm asked properly.
康尼马拉的莎拉·杜根小姐  你愿意和我跳支舞吗
Lady Sarah of Connemara, will you dance with me?
罗伯茨  剃刀党的人混进来了
Roberts. The Peaky Blinders are here.
我告诉过你  肯波先生  他很有种  就是他
I told you, Mr Kimber. He's got some balls, that one.
那个女人的身材可真好啊
And she's got some body, that one.
交点粉笔钱吧
Chalk for your blackboards.
五美元一支
Five pounds a stick.
很高兴跟你做生意
It's a pleasure doing business with you.
你好啊  雷兹  生意怎么样啊
Hello, Raz. How's business?
他妈的  给我起来
Fucking...get up!
狗日的
Fucking...
别动  雷兹  否则我把你另一个耳朵也割掉
Stay still, Raz, or I'll take the whole ear off.
你可需要耳朵才能听见声音呢
And you're going to need your ears to listen.
不准再敲诈勒索比利·肯波的手下了
No more chalking on Billy Kimber's boys.
明白吗
Right?
我们现在是他们的保护伞
We're the protection now.
我把你这盗取的钱征收了
I commandeer this stolen money
记住这是剃刀党的命令
by order of the Peaky Blinders.
要么是你的左腿比你的右腿强健
Either your left leg is stronger than your right
要么就是我们在偷偷逃跑
or we're making a getaway.
-都不是  -我希望这跟刀片什么的无关
- Neither. - I hope this doesn't involve razor blades.
我只是想上升一个等级
I've decided to move up in the world.
成为一个合法的商人
Become a legitimate businessman.
-天啊  你是认真的  -我一直都是认真的
- My gosh. You're serious. - I'm always serious.
我们一路追着李氏家族的人
We chased the Lees across the track,
就沿着德文路往下跑
right the way down the Devon road.
我们把钱都拿回来了
We got every penny back.
礼服真漂亮  你可以穿去我的酒吧
Nice dress. You can wear that to my pub.
请兄弟们喝杯酒  有人受伤吗
Buy the boys a drink. Anybody hurt?
就割伤和淤青而已
A few cuts and bruises.
我们快走吧  莎拉小姐
Off we go, Lady Sarah.
-走路注意点  -借过
- Steady on... - Excuse me.
你的钱  肯波先生
Your money, Mr. Kimber.
从李氏兄弟手里抢回来的
Rescued from the Lee brothers
现在钱归原主
and returned to you
请求你认真听我说一次
with a request for a fair hearing.
你自己的安保队伍并不奏效  肯波先生
Your own protection is failing, Mr. Kimber.
你的手下被人敲诈欺凌
Your boys are taking cuts.
我建议从今往后
I want to suggest that from now on,
你把赛马场的安保工作都承包给剃刀党
you contract out your racetrack security to the Peaky Blinders.
我们能让你少花不少冤枉钱  肯波先生
We would be saving you a lot of money, Mr. Kimber.
一大笔钱
A lot of money.
作为回报  你给我们
In return, you give us...
获利的5%
..5% of the take
及塞文河北岸每次比赛当中
and three legal betting pitches
三场合法赌马的操控权
at every race meeting north of the River Severn,
一年后提高到获利的6%
rising to six after one year
前提是我们双方都对此工作满意的话
if we are all satisfied with the service.
你怎么想  肯波先生
What do you say, Mr. Kimber?
我看  你还是去和我的会计谈生意吧
I say you talk business to my accountant.
我要跳舞
I want to dance.
你的同伴说我可以跟你跳这支舞
Your man said it was all right for me to have this dance.
你一次能派出多少人同时执勤
How many men can you put in the field at one time?
现在失业的人可不少
There's a lot of men out of work at the moment.
每位赌注登记人配两名保镖
Two guards for every bookie.
每次赛马都如此吗
At every meeting?
我们跟一些吉普赛人中的好人有联系
We have contacts with good people among the gypsies.
我们总能提前知道李氏家族准备袭击哪里
We'll always know where the Lees plan to attack.
现在到处在罢工  世道又乱
With all the strikes and troubles,
警察根本靠不住
you can't depend on the police.
不管怎样  我们更坦诚
Anyway...we're more honest.
看来你们两个要成交了
Looks like you two are making a deal.
我们有进展
We are making progress.
那让我再加上一个小附加条件
Then let me throw a small condition into the mix.
听着  我们要去肯波家吃饭
So, listen...we're going to go for dinner at Kimber's house.
他在几英里远的地方有一栋别墅
He has a place a couple of miles away.
我得先去跟他的会计谈点生意  所以
I have some business to settle first with his accountant, so...
你先去  跟肯波一起
You go on ahead, with Kimber.
只有我跟他吗
Just me and him?
对  我这里完事了就去  没问题吧
Yeah...until I'm done here. Is that all right?
我会多付你三英镑  算是补贴这多余的活儿
I'll throw in an extra three quid for your extra time.
你认为我是个出来卖的妓女
You think I'm a whore?
每个人都是出来卖的  格蕾丝
Everybody's a whore, Grace.
只不过出卖的东西不尽相同罢了
We just sell different parts of ourselves.
你说过想要为我工作
You said you wanted to work for me.
想为我工作  你得机灵点
To do that, you have to sharpen up.
我们说好让他跟你独处两个小时
The deal is I give him two hours with you.
他觉得自己是大众情人
He thinks he's a ladies' man.
他认为自己能勾引你
He thinks he can seduce you.
如果你不愿意  可以攻击他的下体
Whenever you want, just kick him in the balls.
我是合同条款中的一项
I'm a clause in a contract.
如果你想要加入我的组织
If you want to be part of my organisation,
你就得做点牺牲
you have to make sacrifices.
说好了吗
Do we have a deal?
给你点甜头  你可以去勾搭一下我那位
As a sweetener, you can try your luck with mine.
是的  说好了
Yes, we have a deal.
-两个小时吗  -对
- Two hours? - Yeah.
赌个大的  赌十镑我一小时内就能上了她
Side bet. Ten pounds says I'll have her fucked in one.
小姐请吧
Mademoiselle.
我猜他说你可以上我  对不对
I bet he said you could have me, didn't he?
而他能去享用她
While he has her.
就是这么安排的  对吗
That's the arrangement, isn't it?
你那位可能是个妓女
Yours might be a prostitute,
但我不是
but I'm not.
我初遇他时  是个女帽制作师
I was a milliner when I met him.
我是个独立的女人
I was independent.
这顶帽子是我做的
I made this hat.
我做帽子的手艺很不错
I was a good milliner.
你的帽子很漂亮
It's a very pretty hat.
真的很漂亮
It really is.
那她是个妓女吗
So is she a prostitute?
说真话吗
God's honest truth?
我不知道她是什么人
I don't know what she is.
你之前在赛马场让我颜面尽失啊
You showed me up back there at the races.
不过你来教教我该如何跳舞吧
Why don't you teach me how to dance properly?
音乐太慢了  放查尔斯顿舞曲吧
The music is too slow. Put on a Charleston.
那我们就离得太远了  我想跟你这样跳舞
Then we'd be far away. I want to dance like this.
拜托  你之前身体可没这么僵硬  不是吗
Come on. You weren't so stiff back there, were you?
你来过这么大的别墅吗
You ever been in a house this big?
瞧瞧你
Look at you.
你简直像一位电影明星
You look like a bloody film star.
我想抽烟
I want a cigarette.
快看  我东西掉了  把它捡起来
Oh, look, I dropped something. Pick it up.
你自己捡
Pick it up yourself.
你他妈就是个酒吧女招待
You're a fucking barmaid.
如果我的杯子掉了  你得捡起来
If I drop a glass on the floor, you pick it up.
我想看你把它捡起来
I want to watch you pick it up.
好了  你个小骚货  我本来不想动粗的
Right, you little slag. I have tried to be nice.
如果我的杯子掉到地上了
If I drop a glass on the floor,
你弯下腰
you bend over
然后捡起那该死的杯子  明白吗
and fucking pick up the fucking glass, OK?
-怎么回事  -不行  先生  不
- What?! - No, sir...no.
你跑来干什么  我还有一个小时呢
What are you doing here? I've got another hour.
稍等一下  听我说  好好听我说
Just wait - listen to me. Just listen to me.
我本打算就让你这么做了  但最后
I was going to let you go through with it, but in the end,
我的良知唤醒了我
my conscience got the better of me.
她外表看起来不错
She looks good on the outside...
但她得了性病
but she has the clap.
没错  是梅毒
Yeah. Syphilis.
当你对她很中意时  我想我可以利用她
When you took a shine to her, I thought I'd use her.
有人告诉我她得了梅毒
Somebody told me she had syph
我心想"有什么关系"
and I thought, "What the hell?"
你就当我这是良心发现吧
Call it my better nature.
她  她是个妓女
She's...she's a whore.
-出去到车里等我  -我自己能走
- Just go and wait in the car. - I can walk on my own!
我们能握下手  然后忘掉这一切吗
Can we shake hands and forget this ever happened?
今天开始时  我是康尼马拉的莎拉·杜根小姐
Start of the day, I was Lady Sarah of Connemara.
最后  我是个得了性病的妓女
By the end, I was a whore with the clap.
你他妈是个混蛋  那样把我卖了
You're a fucking bastard, offering me like that.
但之后你改了主意
But then you changed your mind.
你为什么改变主意了  汤玛斯
Why did you change your mind, Thomas?